<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.18">
  <compounddef id="frontpage" kind="page">
    <compoundname>frontpage</compoundname>
    <title>Overview</title>
    <briefdescription>
    </briefdescription>
    <detaileddescription>
<para> <mcss:class xmlns:mcss="http://mcss.mosra.cz/doxygen/" mcss:class="m-block m-success" /></para>
<para><simplesect kind="par"><title>What is Pressio?</title><para>An open-source project aimed at enabling leading-edge projection-based reduced order models (pROMs) for dynamical systems in science and engineering.</para>
</simplesect>
</para>
<sect2 id="frontpage_1autotoc_md23">
<title>Motivation</title>
<para>Projection-based model reduction refers to a class of surrogate models that reduce the number of degrees of freedom in the high-fidelity model through a projection process. This projection step applied to the governing equations often enables one to make stronger performance guarantees (e.g., of structure preservation, of accuracy via adaptivity) than other surrogates like data-fits and perform more accurate <emphasis>a posteriori</emphasis> error analysis (e.g., via <emphasis>a posteriori</emphasis> error bounds or error models).</para>
<para>Despite these benefits, the practical challenges of implementing model-reduction techniques in large-scale codes often precludes their adoption in practice; this occurs because standard implementations require modifying low-level operations and solvers for each simulation code of interest. This implementation strategy is not practical or sustainable in many modern settings, because industrial simulation codes often evolve rapidly, institutions may employ dozens of simulation codes for different analyses, and commercial codes typically do not expose the required low-level operators and solvers.</para>
<para> <mcss:class xmlns:mcss="http://mcss.mosra.cz/doxygen/" mcss:class="m-block m-success" /></para>
<para><simplesect kind="par"><title>Objective</title><para>To mitigate the implementation burden of projection-based model reduction in large-scale applications without compromising performance.</para>
</simplesect>
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="frontpage_1autotoc_md24">
<title>Main steps of pROMs</title>
<para>Projection-based model reduction can be broken into three main steps, namely data collection, basis creation, and ROM deployment.</para>
<para><itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>data collection: <mcss:span xmlns:mcss="http://mcss.mosra.cz/doxygen/" mcss:class="m-text m-danger">todo</mcss:span> (all)</para>
</listitem><listitem><para>compute basis: <mcss:span xmlns:mcss="http://mcss.mosra.cz/doxygen/" mcss:class="m-text m-danger">todo</mcss:span> (all)</para>
</listitem><listitem><para>create/run the ROM: <mcss:span xmlns:mcss="http://mcss.mosra.cz/doxygen/" mcss:class="m-text m-danger">todo</mcss:span> (all)</para>
</listitem></itemizedlist>
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="frontpage_1autotoc_md25">
<title>What steps does Pressio currently cover?</title>
<para><bold><emphasis>Pressio</emphasis></bold> currently contains capabilities to perform the last step.  <mcss:span xmlns:mcss="http://mcss.mosra.cz/doxygen/" mcss:class="m-text m-danger">todo</mcss:span> Say that we have plans for the other steps too. Maybe at some point we will provide tools to run the samples, but for now that is not a huge priority. we can develop something later on to aid this step. For example interfacing with efficient POD libraries, providing tools for specific mesh formats (exodus).</para>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="frontpage_1autotoc_md26">
<title>The Pressio framework</title>
<para><bold><emphasis>Pressio</emphasis></bold> is a computational <emphasis>framework</emphasis>, comprising a (growing) collection of repositories :</para>
<para><itemizedlist>
<listitem><para><ulink url="https://github.com/Pressio/pressio">pressio</ulink>: <emsp/><ensp/><emsp/><emsp/><ensp/>core C++ library based on generic programming;</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><ulink url="https://github.com/Pressio/pressio4py">pressio4py</ulink>: <emsp/><emsp/><nonbreakablespace/><nonbreakablespace/>Python bindings for the core Pressio C++ functionalities;</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><ulink url="https://github.com/Pressio/pressio-builder">pressio-builder</ulink>: <nonbreakablespace/><nonbreakablespace/><nonbreakablespace/>auxiliary bash scripts for building/testing;</para>
</listitem><listitem><para><ulink url="https://github.com/Pressio/pressio-tutorials">pressio-tutorials</ulink>: <nonbreakablespace/>tutorials explaining how to use <computeroutput>pressio</computeroutput> and its functionalities.</para>
</listitem></itemizedlist>
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="frontpage_1autotoc_md27">
<title>Where to go from here</title>
<para>If you are new and want to learn more, start from the <ref refid="userguide" kindref="compound">User Guide</ref> and see how to install and use pressio, or you can jump directly to the <ref refid="tutorials" kindref="compound">Tutorials</ref> and/or <ref refid="examples" kindref="compound">Examples</ref>. </para>
</sect2>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
